LAWRENCE MAGEE

1621 W. Pacific Coast HWY. Wilmington, CA 90744 | +1 310 347 0887 | lawrence.magee@outlook.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated IT Consultant with 10 years of progressive experience. An energetic self-starter and team builder. Navigates high-stress situations and achieves goals on time and under budget. Currently pursuing a Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science with a minor in Business Analytics, expected date of graduation June 2024.

EXPERIENCE

06/1999 to 12/2019 IT Specialist

U.S. ARMY NATIONAL GUARD — Las Vegas, Nevada, United States

- More than 10 years of leadership experience.
- Enhanced diverse IT projects from idea to completion, including process changes, improvements, and implementation.
- Offered comprehensive VIP support knowledge, aiding effective service desk operations.
- Spearheaded new system installations effectively, ensuring timely distribution for minimized disruption to productivity.
- Enhanced company productivity and performance through the strategic development of internal IT systems.
- Oversaw preventative and emergency maintenance across diverse
 IT systems and services for optimized company output.
- Educated service users on new software updates and system capabilities.

07/2017 to 10/2019 Force Protection Officer

TRIPLE CANOPY — Kuwait City, Kuwait

- Inspected products and services to comply with quality standards.
- Verified and approved US Government personnel, contractor personnel, authorized visitors, and Coalition.
- Forces Inspected all deliveries and vehicles into secured areas of military operations.
- Diffused challenging situations using conflict management techniques.
- Spoke to customers in multiple languages to resolve problems and answer questions.
- Controlled and operated US Government-installed barrier devices to deny unauthorized vehicle access to US Government installations.

04/2012 to 11/2017 IT Help Desk Agent

US ARMY — Las Vegas, Nevada, United States

- Help desk
- Supervised a communications team of 20 personnel, tasked with installing and maintaining Military IT network infrastructure.

- Provided technical information to users and clients through easy-tounderstand presentations and demonstrations.
- Designed and perfected effective data recovery strategies to manage unexpected data loss or theft.
- Acted as the direct point of contact for any escalations from first-line engineers.

02/2016 to 01/2017 Operations Manager

US ARMY — Taji, Iraq

- Trained and mentored a high-performing team through regular performance reviews, individual feedback, and professional coaching.
- Analyzed strategic, core, and support processes, recommending improvements to streamline or automate procedures.
- Directed daily operations by spearheading the implementation of short-term and long-term strategies to achieve business plan and profitability objectives.
- Trained personnel on optimal processes and use of equipment, boosting unit efficiency.

02/2012 to 01/2013 Field Service Technician

DIGITAL INTELLIGENCE SYSTEMS, DISYS — Las Vegas, Nevada, United States

- Performed user data migration on over 300 Windows 7 and XP machines.
- Installed TSA applications and software on DHS machines.
- Inspected tools, machinery, and equipment on an established schedule to verify functionality and safety.
- Performed administrative tasks pertaining to adding and deleting user accounts in Windows Active Directory.
- Worked closely with DHS security personnel performing successful data migration and transfer of user accounts in Secure Contained Information Facilities.
- Performed and monitored encrypted server activation and deactivation.
- Replaced malfunctioning or defective components and wiring to restore full function.
- Performed and monitored end-of-life process for the destruction of secure DHS hard drives and Legacy computer systems.
- Received new computer systems and monitored end-of-day closeout process for old Legacy systems.

02/2010 to 01/2012 Network Administrator

US ARMY — Qalat, Afghanistan

- Oversaw the installation of network operating systems (NOS) servers.
- Implemented Microsoft Exchanges Servers.
- Implemented DHCP Servers.
- Corrected LAN malfunctions.
- Supervised a team that maintained and operated over 15 servers

- and supported 250 user workstations.
- Provided desktop, laptop, and server support, reducing operational downtime due to system faults.
- Successfully resolved over 80% of Secure IP router network security issues.
- Assisted in the installation of IP radio and Satellite transmission systems using TDMA and FDMA protocols to ensure redundant VoIP and data network access.
- Set up and managed a USO for US and NATO coalition forces including but not limited to using a spectrum analyzer to acquire transmission feed for the AFN television network.
- Directed the physical security for more than 30 Command Post Nodes, Cisco routers, and switches.
- Implemented and updated 3 different enclaves of Network Access.

05/2001 to 10/2004

Operations Manager

GATEWAY COMPUTERS LLC — Chicago, Illinois, United States

- Oversaw financial management activities, including budget management, accounting, and payroll.
- Trained and mentored a high-performing team through regular performance reviews, individual feedback, and professional coaching.
- Analyzed strategic, core, and support processes, recommending improvements to streamline or automate procedures.
- Resolved quality control and customer service issues that could not be resolved at the CSR (Customer Service Representative) level.
- Had creative control over the store site for the design and placement of home and business solutions and system displays.
- Assisted in Gateway store upgrades installing cable and setting up network switches and hubs.
- Boosted operational efficiencies through forecasting and budget management.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Java
- Python
- Data entry
- Technical issues analysis
- Technical documents comprehension Hardware upgrades
- Systems administration
- Data processing
- System design
- Operating system deployment Systems configuration
- Cybersecurity

- Staff education and training
- Operating system deployment
- System configuration
- Infrastructure development
- Call center experience
- Knowledgeable in Mac systems
- Software diagnosis
- LAN aptitude
- Customer service expert
- Troubleshooting proficiency
- Skilled in TCP/IP and WAN

Virtualization

EDUCATION

2024 BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Maryland — Adelphi, Maryland

2010 **NETWORK ADMIN**: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Gordon Signal Center — Augusta, Georgia

2009 Help Desk Agent: Information Systems

US Army Network Management Course — Salt Lake City, Utah

2000 INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND COMPUTER: Information Technology

FT Gordon Signal Center — Augusta, Georgia